But the solar system's maintaining it equally at 3.6 amps, okay, at 28.2 volts, okay.
So 100 watt hours and inside the house we're drawing 42, I'm trying to see why we're drawing
42.
Oh, people charging laptops and shit?
Maybe.
Okay.
So I'm going to turn on semi-green inverter, my lovely 50 hertz inverter with this.
This is the 50 hertz inverter?
Yeah.
The 3000 watt monstrosity?
And it's a, you know, if you had good ratings, I'd just say the Trenum M started the wrong
thing in the wrong place.
If you look at the bottom of it, so, so now generators are off, the inverter floating
boat barely went up like a tenth of an amp, okay, because it was rated to have pretty
good, you know, you know, parasitic load when there's no load.
So what exactly is this box?
This is the solar charge.
That's the solar charge control.
Okay.
So solar power.
That's all the brains.
So the solar power comes in from up there, so this conduit up to there, brings underground.
I also have other wires going out there.
I actually have a AC outlet up there in that box, just to run like telescopes and things.
Gotcha.
And right now it comes from the main generator.
I want to move this to semi-green, okay.
This is semi-green.
That's semi-green.
This is green near me, no, this is actually, that's that green.
This is the solar panel.
You basically leave this on unless you're servicing the batteries, okay.
Okay.
By the way, the way these switches are, these DC shut-off high-amp switches is horizontal
is on.
So, for example, I just turned on the big interval at times, I turned it off, it will
squeal at death-dye, okay, as this big, massive capacitor slowly gives it a go.
And that's that.
And that turns off all the parasitic load.
There actually is a remote, like RJ45, that I can turn it on, but it, but it all it does,
and all of them are this way, all it does is, it's a fast on-off, it reduces it, but
turns off the power, but there is a parasitic load.
Gotcha.
I'll put it back on, we'll have it on for the day.
That means the lights in the bathroom and the bedroom will work on semi-green, because
all the new outlets I put in are on semi-green, okay.
So semi-green is on, then this is battery disconnect, you always leave it on unless
you're servicing the batteries, okay.
So when I leave camp, when I leave camp, I turn this off, this off, in the summer I
flip this down to on always, this is the DC power to this, okay.
Okay.
One of the things I want to do is replace, I have a lot of low power fuses on everything,
like these, I want to put this block in somewhere and make a nice fuse block, okay.
It's a fuse block for my low amperage.
So I have a fuse going over to the fridge in there, I have, this thing is fused, because
this is not a Halana amperage, so he comes up here, and then if I flip this, if I, so
with semi-green, and before I had solar, if I turn this timer here, and then I flip this
up to timer, it stays on, okay.
But now when this timer times out, it will turn off this inverter and turn off super
green.
Got it.
Okay.
And, and I actually have the, you know, sort of die here, okay.
But super green can basically just stay on all the time.
Well, yeah, well, it can stay on all the time, you know, one thing, the circuits still on
the super green are the light above the desk, the light above the kitchen sink, and, and
the gadget charging station on the stairs, because those outlets were run for, I am going
to move those circuits, except for the desk itself, to super green, semi-green, I mean,
okay.
So this is super green from this inverter, comes to here, and this is just an AC status
thing that you plug in, you can unplug it, and it turns out off, that's all about it.
Okay, so that just reads, that just reads like output?
That just reads output, and what it is, there is a shunt here.
This is a shunt coil, AC shunt coil that measures my amperage.
So this, notice this goes into there.
So this is just, you know, so I'm trying to, I mean, put this together, okay.
Yeah.
Amazon.
Okay.
They, they, they, um, so that's, that's that, and then obviously if I unplug this, this is
just, you know, yeah, and, and it's low, low current, you know, and, and, and, uh,
so when I'm here by myself, I often just run on this alone.
Gotcha.
Okay.
So let's see.
The output from this guy goes all the way, and then into here, into here, then this goes
out over to, oh, goes, goes, actually goes to an outlet in the garage where much, okay.
So in the garage, so this is, this is, um, um, I have two big circuits.
I have a 240 volt, uh, three, uh, split phase circuit going from the big generator straight
into the house.
Okay.
Into the garage.
Oh, we're going to the garage.
So let me finish out here.
Sure.
Uh, actually let's go in the garage.
I'll explain the panels there and what I want to do there.
And then I'll come out and spray.
How that's all of this shit's why it is with those relays that pretty out.
Okay.
So coming in from the garage, that is the, uh, that big fat wire is, is, is the, uh,
128, 240, a split phase.
It comes to this main panel here.
Okay.
Actually it comes to this.
When I turn on this generator, which I will do right now, I have a switch here.
Okay.
So the big, the big generator starting electric start, the water system turns it on.
This turns it on.
That's the 6,000 watt one.
One, two, three.
Clunk.
Time to lay relay in there.
Okay.
With a timer inside.
I melt that.
And that means I'm not cranking against load.
Gotcha.
Okay.
When the pump calls.
And then it comes into this sub panel.
Okay.
Now what it does do is, um, this, this, this circuit is a 30 amp circuit going to be the
power into the house where I have another panel.
This is actually the master panel, a sub panel in the basement.
This was one of the first circuits I put in the place when I put the generator in.
And, and so this, this, that, the outlets in the house from the early days just came
off of this.
Uh, uh, uh, I've moved a number of those circuits to a green panel in the basement.
I'll show you that in a bit.
Cool.
That is now going to be semi-green.
Well, super green just goes straight from there.
There is no circuit breaker because the fuse on the, the fuse on the inverter will blow.
Okay.
And that little inverter, this is semi-green.
Semi-green actually goes from a, so I'm going to go back and explain to you semi-green because
I do have a circuit breaker panel there, um, uh, under that inverter.
But I also, um, there's also, uh, it will pull from the generator circuit.
I'll, I'll go explain the generators connection to all this later.
This is circuit number six, uh, uh, so here off of this circuit, it seems like.
Uh, lights in here over there and light in that outlet over there.
Gotcha.
Uh, uh, there's just an outlet up here and that's, and that runs off of super green.
No, that, well, right now it's off generator only.
Okay.
That's all the generator out there.
I'm going to order all the super green.
Semi-green.
Okay.
Semi-green is.
Semi-green is, semi-green is kind of a goal.
The semi-green is a goal for everything because you can get high current either 3001 inverter
or if a generator is running.
Yeah.
Okay.
Generator straight.
So the generator is so that the battery charger out there, which also runs off of generators
only.
Okay.
The battery charger that sits there, feet, either the, either the small little portable
or the big generator, whenever a generator is running, the battery charger will put battery
charge on the batteries, but you're not drawing from the batteries at the same time.
So the inverter, so the batteries will charge up faster.
Cool.
Okay.
Cause I, you know, uh, uh, and so rather than a lot of people make off grid source systems
that the generator sold job is to charge batteries.
Okay.
And, and then your, your inverter is always providing continuous power 24 by seven and,
and with the new inverter charger I can have, it will actually have an inverter charger.
And I may actually go to that, that will start to gen, the big generator when necessary,
especially if the battery charger is more than the 25 amp 24 volt charger I have out
now.
You can get like a 50 amp one that can put a pretty fast charge to generator, don't
have to run a huge amount of time.
Okay.
So that's an option.
I may rewire that when I replace that, that, that 50 Hertz thing.
But so super green, super green when I wired this, before I had this, I wired super green
in from here and it wasn't called super green.
It was on my 1500 watt 12 volt inverter before the one I had before, but switch to 24 volt
last year.
Right.
I remember that.
Okay.
So, so, uh, but I just moved the existing solar circuit over to, uh, uh, super green
and then now I'm, I'm, I'm making semi green when I added this new 3000 watt inverter.
So this is the only semi green outlet here.
This is a full charger timer and it turns right now, it's on super green.
That charges these.
I'm going to move this to this and make more outlets out here on this.
Wait, you got tool charge on super green?
It was because it was the original, it was the original 12 volt system, which was a 1500
watt.
I still have that inverter in a box somewhere.
Okay.
I have, I have a complete 12 volt setup in boxes and actually, you know, somebody wants
a real small 12 volt setup, everything, but the panels, the, uh, so believe it or not,
uh, uh, then when we organize the garage this summer, we put all these, I used to have these
in the house and everything.
Yeah.
Uh, we put them all on this circuit and believe it or not, charging a bunch of these batteries
plus running the thing is too much for super green.
So yeah.
I'll probably keep one super green outlet out here.
I'll probably swap this to be super green and this to be, uh, semi-green.
And then over here, generator only air compressor, I'll probably keep it on generator only.
Okay.
You know, the, uh, you know, the, I don't know, I'd not have a generator, but the lights
and even the tool outlet over there, I'm going to, I'm going to move this.
Okay.
So that one is the lights and tool outlet over here and that one is currently on generator.
Uh, this is add comes right into the, this is a Jane generator panel.
Okay.
And that guy is the compressor plus generator lights.
All right.
Now let me go back over to where the generator, and by the way, one circuit comes out of here,
uh, uh, and the circuit coming out of here goes up to here to the compressor circuit and
then goes back to the generator so that when the generator is running, so I have it, and
it goes through a 15 amp, uh, uh, 15 amp breaker to code and back to the generator, the generator
takes whatever the generator is running, it adds the ability, uh, to charge its own battery
from AC.
Okay.
And, but so, so the circuit, this circuit here, yeah, comes from the garage.
Okay, this is output, this is from 120 volt from the garage on the right.
Okay.
And by the way, that home wire is the two-wire start circuit.
Oh, sick.
Okay.
Cause that's just a 12 volt on the battery.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Now in here, this is, let's say this thing totally shits the bed.
Yeah.
I get a big sort of heavy duty 240 volt portable generator and I flip this double breaker in
one direction on from backup generator.
Okay.
Generic.
Come over here, emergency gen backup, plug in there using this cord.
Okay.
And a manual start, but, and I put this in long ago when I put the generator.
Yeah, yeah.
Now, more recently, since I do want to have charge, I put an input in here from 1000 watt
or 2000 watt right now, it's a 2000 watt.
And this is input from my semi-green portable.
So these either the big generator or this input, this is an input, okay, from here.
From here.
Okay.
So this is where the, this is where.
I ran this all last night.
Right.
This is super quiet.
It's got a low RPM and burner mode.
Okay.
We can run all night if necessary.
Or if I, if it's a cloudy day and I'm telecommuting, it's not super noisy like this and a lot less
wear and tear on a big machine.
Yeah.
This is 6kW.
And I run it, when it's running super efficient, it's putting out about a half a kW.
But it's enough to run the battery charger.
Gotcha.
And by the way, because of the cloudy, that panel feeds 12 volts through this PWM solar
charge controller that feeds back through here, comes back through that red and black
wire into here to keep that battery charge, okay, because, don't put that switch off in
the garage in the generator, we don't need it on.
Switch on the garage.
Okay.
Let's see if I can remember this.
There's one, wait.
Which one?
Fuck.
Compressor switch.
Oh, right, right, right, right, right.
Oh, enabled disable.
Gotcha.
Okay.
Made a noise.
So there's one, two, three switches in here, plus that dial.
All right.
Fuck.
This is complicated.
This is so complicated.
I know.
Oh, here.
Okay.
Has a computer.
Computer.
This thing sucks, right?
Yeah.
Well, it, it, it runs everything, but it's a parasitic load of about 8 watts.
8 watts.
Off the battery.
If I'm here by myself in the generator and hardly runs, this battery goes down.
So the, but right now this battery is fully charged.
This measures the charge level on that battery.
Okay.
It's a totally separate, and these go straight to that little 100 watt panel on the bottom
of there.
That's solar in and coming from load out.
This goes back.
So this also feeds in, in here.
This, no, this, yeah, this goes into here, a 12 volt, oh, that's the negative.
I'm sorry.
That's the negative here.
So this, oh yeah, the red for this actually goes down to charge this.
So if, if I'm running any generator, this actually will add a more charge.
This is such a slow charger.
This is designed for home standby, meaning you've got utility.
You've got utility.
This computer has its own little very low current battery charger to keep the battery
topped off.
The generator is running, the generator is keeping the battery topped off, so the battery
is always topped off.
Yeah.
We don't have fucking utility.
Okay.
So if the generator is off and there's no power, otherwise I think this computer will
kill it over the course of four days.
Been there, done that.
Yeah.
Okay.
And that fucking blows.
And so, so I have this whole separate system with its own battery charge.
So this is a complete, you know, completely separate battery charger right there.
Battery charger, solar charge controller, solar panel, and battery, you know.
And hopefully the idea is that the eight watts from there is outweighed by that hundred
watts there.
Over the course of 24 hours.
Okay.
But if I, you know, but the nice thing is if I run either that or this, this goes off.
Got it.
Okay.
Like, like for example, notice it was on and flashing.
Yeah.
But.
Did I have gas?
Get a little bit.
I'm gonna have to.
Oh, did it run out overnight?
No, it didn't.
All right.
So the relays in there will prep, this will preempt this and either this or this will
preempt the solar charge controller on semi-green.
On semi-green.
Okay.
So yeah, I'm going to top it off tonight because we may have to run it tonight depending
on what we do.
The interesting about it is I can turn, we can let people turn on all the lights inside
the bedrooms off with that band and then plug in all their gadgets onto the semi-green
circuit.
That's what I'm saying.
Charge your phones in your bedrooms.
Yeah.
Okay.
Not in the charge.
Because the charge station is super green, which is purely solar and solar is not happening
right now.
It's not only purely solar battery, but it's only 300 watts.
Right.
Because it would, it's heritage dates to.
Yeah.
All these fucking phones now use like 15 watt chargers and shit and like 30 watt chargers.
Well they quickly dropped down to a much lower current weight.
It's glass tops, dead glass tops, five dead glass tops will blow out the super green.
And so you said that there was a fuse attached to the super green and that's like not a reusable
fuse.
That just like.
Yeah.
It's actually, it's on the inverter itself.
Cool.
Okay.
Yeah.
And I have blown that.
Actually what happens is half the time the thing goes beep and shuts off.
Ah, cause it'll, it'll smart enough to recognize that it's over current and it'll peace out.
But it, you know, the nice thing is, is that super green is enough with my very low current
and that's why I got the Euro.
My brother Jeff installed the Nero and this, the one you helped survey and I was looking
at his power consumption.
I go, fuck.
And that's why I got it.
I mean, I gave up a lot of networking functionality like VLANs and, you know, it does now port
in.
So let me put this on now.
On.
Yeah.
Sometimes when you start these things and then you turn them on for me.
So now, now what is happening is, um, that charger's on.
Right now everything's happy and fully charged.
Yeah.
The sun is happy.
That charger says fully charged.
So, but power is coming from there through here, into here, by the way, that has its
own overload protection.
So it's not directly fused.
Okay.
That generator.
Gotcha.
Okay.
But when it comes through the big generator comes from the 15 amp fuse on.
So semi green is 15 amps.
So that's like 1800 watts.
Okay, it's a single circuit, not really to code, you know, got too many outlets on it
with you.
Okay.
So the battery charger's charging, but and, and, uh, semi green inverter is on and, you
know, so everything's in the house.
So semi green inverters not have any load because this green, this, this breaker here,
the preamp should relay, uh, from, uh, Jenset preamp and then over here is semi green Jenset
preamp solar.
So basically if both generators, the big one, the 15 amp circuit that comes back from the
garage from the big generator, the, the circuit from that small plug, yeah, coming to this
relay, if the big generator runs, now if I put your hand on here.
Okay.
What am I supposed to feel?
What?
Listen.
Wait.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
It switched to the big generator.
Yeah.
Okay.
After the generator started.
Put your hand back on it.
Where's this?
Where's my indicator light?
So.
That's on generator.
Over here.
Okay.
Now it's on the little generator.
Go turn.
Uh, hang on.
I'm just going to plug it here.
Uh, what?
Take a look.
Okay.
I'm going to plug in the generator.
Oh.
Now it's on the little generator.
Okay.
Go turn.
Uh, hang on.
I'm just going to plug it here.
Uh.
I'm going to plug in the generator.
Oh.
Now it's on inverter.
Yeah.
50 fucking hertz.
Okay.
Uh, uh, isn't that nice?
Yeah.
That's fucking sick.
Okay.
I'm plugging it back in.
So what exactly is this device?
So this is a two pole, uh, uh, two pole, uh, uh, relay.
Two pole relay.
Okay.
And this is the same thing.
Gotcha.
So literally like what happens is.
What's that big electrical?
That's big.
Granger supply.
Okay.
Awesome.
Yeah.
For sure.
Okay.
So, so if I understand this correctly, like you've got like the, the, the arm of the relay,
right?
Like hooked up to.
Normally closed in one direction.
Right.
And then when, when power is.
Normally closed for everything means it's going to pull from here.
Right.
Power from, from, from, from big generator hits here.
Yeah.
So power from big generator here, here it switches it to big generator.
Okay.
So what power comes into here?
It then goes to here.
If power comes from here, it's the fault node is with no power called to the, to the coil
is from inverter, but when any generator is running, this one flips.
So you feel this one flip in either case, you get a flicker.
Okay.
So the, the.
So now I'm just running the big generator for no fucking reason.
Fucking hell.
And I'm going to turn off.
This is a 22 minute long video.
Oh, I heard a, I heard a click.
So now the, now this boy's off back on this guy and this guy pulls from batteries.
Yeah.
That pulls from the batteries, which is of course charged by that big fuck off thing over
there.
So if the summer, believe it or not, I can, you know, if I have a well good summer, summer
day, I just leave some green on and the generators only runs on the pump and I don't need the
portable.
Okay.
You know, and if I actually added a little bit more batteries would be better, but I've
got 800 amp hours.
I'll get you there in a second.
So that's basically this circuitry here.
Okay.
Let's go and take a look at the basement.
Sweet.
Parasig load.
Yeah.
From a distance, you can tell the generator's running, but I chase every person.
Oh, for sure.
100%.
One more quick question.
What?
So this 15 watt panel right here, that, that charges a battery in here.
One of those, just one of those little batteries.
I had two of them here.
My old hundred watt system had two of these big batteries.
The other one was totally shot.
I turned it in.
It just maintains.
So, you know, if, if a lead acid battery goes too dead, it can freeze and damage.
It's like fucked.
Okay.
And apparently it gets a long time for a big battery like that to go bad.
It would last a couple of years, but yeah.
I heard you said 20 years at some point.
Well it freezing weather.
You know, not good.
That's why like when your car goes dead, the winter and you leave your battery dead and
you let it freeze, because all the sulfur is on the plate and that water in the battery.
Yeah.
Especially a flooded battery.
So you got to fucking buy a new battery.
Yeah.
Refurbish the battery.
I think there's one behind the wood.
Have you recorded what this does?
Turn it on for Wi-Fi.
Yeah.
That was towards the beginning.
Okay.
I got something.
But yeah.
Okay.
Right.
Yeah.
I remember that.
It's like a simple idiot.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Okay.
Yeah.
That's what we're done here.
I gotta send it.
I hope it's fine.
Don't break a leg.
Again.
Bozo.
That bozo broken ankle.
So in here, this was last summer.
Last summer?
A year ago.
Oh shit.
Son.
We got stacks on stacks.
Yeah.
So this assembles.
Okay.
This is gravity fed.
I built this with a river a year ago this summer.
And at the same time, Connor and I put those 400 watt panels over the garage.
Right.
And that had, I had the, I only had to buy one more.
I had three left over from my old original 12 volt setup.
Yeah.
And then this is also a preemptive, this actually actually preemptive circuitry built in.
I bought this to replace that fridge.
Right.
Whatever any generator runs.
Okay.
This comes off.
So this comes off.
This turns on the fridge.
Okay.
That's the fridge.
This is actually a two pole switch.
Yeah.
So it'll switch both the 24 volts straight from the batteries.
And this comes from one of the fuses in there.
24 volts.
And, and so a cigarette ladder, but it's 24 volts.
Wait.
So this is a truckers fridge.
You put this in a semi-track.
Most trucks are truckers.
They semi-track.
He has this for his cold stuff in the, in the back of his, your super cap.
Arguably the most important switch in the camp is that one.
Cause that's the beer fridge.
You got it.
Especially in the summer.
So yeah.
Okay.
And actually, actually it's actually great because I can turn the temperature down
to freeze.
And, and it'll be a freezer.
Nice.
And it's highly efficient.
Yeah.
And then the summer, the solar runs it.
Okay.
Awesome.
And then whenever the generator runs it preempts to the generator.
And it had that, it had the preempts in certain cases.
Okay.
Just because.
So in other words, obviously, you know, the, the, the, you know, the trucker doesn't
want his truck batteries to go dead and he can't start the fucking truck.
So, you know, the, uh, so, uh, yeah, you know, the, not cheap, but $700.
But, uh, yeah.
Oh.
Yeah.
This was a major improvement here.
So.
Nice.
Very cool.
Um, so these batteries kind of pool with the batteries outside.
No, those batteries outside aren't even used anymore.
Okay.
So those batteries.
They're locked over from a 12 volt system.
Gotcha.
All right.
These are the batteries.
I just, I just want that other, other big one is still pretty good.
Okay.
What do you use?
Is it when you're not using that for anything?
I'm not using it for anything, but it could be part of that 12 volt system I give to
somebody.
Okay.
I don't know the parts for the 12 volt system in here.
Ah, this is the, this is the previous gen.
This is what gen, gen two.
Gen one.
What, what gen are we on right now?
So.
Are we on gen two?
We're probably two and a half.
Gen two and a half.
Okay.
So here's my 1000 watt inverter right here.
That's the 1000 watt inverter.
Yeah.
12 volts.
12 volt.
1000 watt inverter.
Not interchangeable.
And I have a solar, what I have.
Actually, I have a 100, 100 watt small inverter.
Oh, this is the 20 per volt one.
I have an extra 20 per one in case that super green one fails.
Right.
And I have a 12 volt one as well.
So yeah.
Cool.
So I have, this is enough.
I have enough to make other than the solar panels to make a complete 12 volt system.
Yeah.
That somebody, somebody who's just here in the summer and has like a very lightweight
internet service like, like my arrow.
Yeah.
You know, and they're not here in the winter.
That could be more than enough for, you know, probably I would just run with four panels
and that inverter, one or two of those bat batteries.
Sure.
And they'd be good to go.
Nice.
And so remind me, why did you switch to 24 volt?
Fatness of wires.
Okay.
The what, the 12 volt wire is coming.
Oh, they're coming from behind.
This is this.
And even these are slightly underrated, but I don't, I don't, since I'm not running,
you know, I don't draw 3,000 watts.
Yeah.
Okay.
And it can take a surge.
But technically this should be, this is, I think four out gauge.
I think it should be, I think four out gauge.
I think it should be two or one odd four, which is like, and, and if I were 12 volt,
it would have to be just fucking and just managing and dealing with it.
They're, they're distance lengths and there's calculations, what you have to have.
Yeah.
And, and, and ideally, you know, I can get double the power if I just switched to 48
volt and I wouldn't even need to change these wires.
Okay.
And I just rewire these.
So these are 12 volt batteries, two banks, each in parallel.
And also, I'll show you how I will draw it on paper because I can show you.
Yes, please.
Okay.
Yeah.
I've got a, I got a sketchbook.
We can, we can do it in there.
It's like actually proper.
You're filming that you're going to be watching this.
This is a 29 minute long video Potter.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'll show you the base.
Okay.
That's just, just a selection of distribution and it needs a lot.
I did some rework this summer.
Okay.
Like all the new wiring we put in to, to, to house helped and a whole bunch of CSU just
helped me wire crawling under the camp.
Also, you know, during the middle of the season.
Fuck.
Was that bad?
That was bad.
Wasn't it?
It was pretty rough.
It was still fun.
All right.
Yeah.
Okay.
I have a light on super green that turns on some, you know, LED lights there.
Yeah.
So this is basement light on a timer, always.
Timers for everything.
More fucking time.
This is the main sub panel from the generator.
Okay.
And I've got a bunch of newsbreakers here that I put them in.
I think I was going to wire the whole house from the main generator.
I'll probably never use all these circuits, but there they are.
There you have them.
Okay.
This is a 240 volt circuit going to the water pump system.
This boy?
Yeah.
Okay.
So interesting for the water pump system it had to do with the generator.
This is a two pole start switch for switch the, so switch the 240 volts with phase.
Yeah.
Normally at a well, you would run 240 volt in and out and it would click on and off the
pump as needed at a house.
Okay.
With utility.
The problem is I need to use one of the poles of this.
Yeah.
It's just a two pole switch.
Okay.
And if I push on this right here.
What are you pushing on?
Click.
I just went out of water.
Now.
Timer goes.
It's pumping.
I just forced it to pump.
Yeah.
It's almost full so it's going to start off any minute, but that turned on that.
That plugged into Gen-O-Me.
Notice I labeled that Gen-O-Me?
Gen-O-Me.
Okay.
And I noticed I labeled that one up there super green.
Super green.
And I didn't, that's a new little distribution box up there that moved some of the wires
from Gen to semi-green and super green.
So I have a split super green.
The upstairs outlet in the loft and in my bedroom is that four wire.
Okay.
So it takes both super green and semi-green upstairs.
The, well, it's full.
There you go.
So all of this, and by the way, so what it's this is, this is, so obviously I need a 12
volt circuit.
The 12 volt start circuit for the generator has to come through all this.
It comes all the way down to this switch.
Comes into here.
This switch disables it so the water can't start the generator.
Disable.
And then if the generator is running, it would actually still get power.
Actually, no, it won't.
It won't get power.
But if you totally want it, you can turn off, this is a 240 volt breaker to the pump.
But normal operation, this is on.
This has been there since I put the generator in back in 2011.
Okay.
And again, this is the start circuit.
This was the CAT 3 cable I stole from RIT.
Oh my fucking god.
Incredible.
But yeah, there's that.
And then I've been building out this new sub panel and he's on semi green.
Okay.
So he comes straight from the semi green.
And I use these extra, this actually was water pump wire.
So when I built the thing, I actually put a lot of extra wire in the conduit from the
garage to the house.
I have not had to put any new wires in.
So I have circuits.
I have cables for three separate sources of 120 volt power from the day I put the generator
in the garage.
Very nice.
Okay.
And it sat there unused.
And it's been very nice.
But right now I have.
So, so these are the new circuits we put in this summer that Klaus and the boys have
saved to help me with.
Danny and Lonnie.
Yeah.
What did that say?
What did that say over there?
Basement, bathroom, kitchen, kitchen net.
But that actually is not hooked up yet.
Okay.
It will be.
I'm going to move the semi green kitchen.
Switch on the floor there.
That switch on the floor is coming off of super green only right now.
Okay.
I got to move that.
I moved that switch on the floor.
Actually, I'm actually going to rewire.
I'm going to wire up to those up above lights.
I like the indirect lights shining on the ceiling.
Yeah.
Okay.
The makes a nice warm light in there.
I have to do more of those.
And so I'm going to just run super green to the desk with the internet and everything
else will be on semi green, especially once I get the right inverter going.
And then, but so the bathroom, I figured I was going to have a separate circuit.
What does this say?
15 amp.
I can't even read my writing there.
I'm terrible.
I'm already terrible.
You've got to get the label maker down here.
I know.
Yeah.
It doesn't stick.
You need a better label maker.
That label maker, they fall off.
Yeah.
They just suck.
Get the class label maker.
I don't know.
I used cheaply.
Fozo.
But yeah, this is just a basic soap panel.
And what happens is I bring three wires in, but I just bring the two hots together because
it's, this is actually, I'm only getting 15 amps.
Now let's, oh, one last thing I didn't show you.
Okay.
Over here.
But it's nice when I arrived in the summer and I disabled my water when I leave in the
summer just so that it doesn't actually start in pulp.
And I disabled my generator.
Yeah.
By the way, I didn't show you my disabled process.
I might as well show you that.
Sure.
So because we're in the garage, the most annoying thing about that computer generator, you're
gonna, you know, I already, Steve Green helped me fix the computer generator one time because
I had to put in Potter designed lightning protection.
Potter designed lightning protection.
Because the computer generator.
It's intense.
Computer was dried by a nearby lightning storm shortly after.
Oh, when was that?
Oh, it's a bunch of years ago.
Okay.
And it was after the warranty of the generator expired and $400 for a new fucking computer.
That blows chunks.
So here, when I leave camp, the Tarte circuit from house and everywhere comes through this
box that I designed.
What's in there?
It's a surge suppression circuit.
Switch on top.
Yeah.
That basically takes all the wire and shunts them to ground.
So here's an honor start for the generator.
I flipped this.
Nothing happened.
Okay.
The computer is still ready to run, but there's any lightning strikes that strikes the ground
and induces through the start circuit is not going to come through to the generator computer.
Okay.
Get pranked.
So ready to run.
So this doesn't know it's not a source.
So I got no way to start.
I can go over here and push it to manual start, but it's on auto start.
Okay.
This putting it to the center position means I can turn this back on.
No startage.
It's on here.
Basically, all these start triggers are just hooked in parallel.
Sometimes where did I turn the generator?
Is the pump pumping?
Is it turned on in the kitchen?
Is it turned on in the garage?
Or is it turned on out here?
You've got to get like a status LED or some shit to like let you know.
Well, I do.
There's lights in various places.
We need like a whole switchboard, like a centralized switchboard somewhere.
But this is a surge suppression circuit and it has a solid state relay.
When I came up here, Steve Green, I had a solid state relay and it fried.
Which was not a bad thing.
It saved the generator.
Steve Green helped me wire this.
But so here's what happens is we'll go through my arrival routine.
So this is always slipped off when I leave camp.
Okay.
Just to ground everything.
Right.
But if the lightning strikes when I'm in camp, that circuitry probably protects me anyway.
Okay.
Yeah.
That surge suppression circuitry I bought.
So this off.
Now, this means the solar charge controller is still topping out the battery.
So no self-discharge.
And nothing will start to generator.
Okay.
I arrive.
This is on.
First thing I come out here.
You always see me come out here.
Yeah, right.
Okay.
I come out here.
Put it up.
Put this on.
On.
I had to, there's a fuse here for the computer.
Oh.
Okay.
Sure.
I used to take out the fuse every time I left.
I got pissed at that.
So I wired the switch.
You got a little switch boy.
There's a fuse.
Okay.
It's a fuse.
It's just, it's just like a 5 amp or 10 amp 12 volt fuse.
Okay.
So turn this puppy on.
Now look at the computer screen.
Generator active install wizard.
It's not ready to run.
Okay.
Oh my God.
I didn't set the time right.
What time is it?
The time is currently in New York.
It actually has stores and flash memory.
It's run log.
11.53.
Okay.
Enter.
Good enough.
Month.
Deal 12.
Today's the 27th.
I did set that.
Okay.
Now I hit enter.
Today's the 28th.
28th.
Oh well.
Fuck it.
And there.
Okay.
Now it's ready to run.
Why the fuck does your generator need a clock?
Fuck it.
And so I got to go through this.
Now here's what's really bad.
Okay.
You're right here.
It's 15 below.
Oh shit.
This LCD.
It takes like five minutes for the digits to show.
With your fingers fucking freezing.
And I want a fucking digger shot.
I got a fucking deal.
But there it is.
And now we're ready to run.
And it will start.
Why didn't it start?
Enter.
Why is that not a run?
Oh did you switch?
Oh I did.
I know.
Oh yeah.
I did put it in.
Thank you.
So that's that.
And then I apparently changed the oil and oil filter and service and motor.
Okay.
Damn sheesh.
So now you've seen the basement.
Did I close up the basement door?
You like shut it.
I don't know if there's like a latch or anything.
No, no, no.
Did I close it?
No.
Yes.
No oh.
Oh.
Celine.
No.
Oh.
And they're professionally done by professionals that charge $20,000.
But that's fucking boring.
Well, yeah.
Well, the...
So now, yeah.
So I've got a few wiring down here to change the circuits going over there.
I do want, you know, so that obviously...
So the inverter's on.
Oh yeah, you can see this.
Okay, I got 3,000 watts.
Okay.
By the way, these are like light activated, so if you...
Have you got close to them?
Yeah, well, if you cover up that little sensor.
Yeah, yeah.
And when it's still enough light.
So this is...
I can run my desk on super green alone.
It's kind of nice.
Just the desk, okay?
Sure.
The desk area.
The microwave's running, okay?
And what's that running on right now?
It's running on the inverter.
That's the inverter.
It's running the generator on?
It's draining the batteries.
It was draining the batteries.
No, not yet.
Wait.
The hammer.
Notice the frequency change of the sound.
Switch from 50 to 60.
That time it actually worked.
Sometimes it would go...
I have a little UPS over here.
You may...
I probably had it.
It would totally bonkers out to UPS.
And that led me, like, into all sorts of confusion.
Good name.
So, yeah, so for example, the light upstairs can be turned on.
The lights in the bedroom can be turned on.
The lights in the bathroom can be turned on.
And, you know, we're pretty charged.
Probably out this evening I'll run the portable generator from dark until about 8.39 or shortly
we could go to bed.
I'll turn it off and the internet alone can run overnight.
Just fine.
Not a issue.
Great.
Off the batteries.
And especially now that the nitro is going to be a bit warmer, the batteries will be
able to get more productive.
And that's the system.
Okay, so now we want to draw things out.
Or do we want to do something else?
Oh, yeah.
I can draw things out.
What are people doing?
People are just kind of doing their own thing.
I'm thinking tomorrow when it's a bit warmer, we'll climb Baldy and have a picnic somewhere.
Just that, bro.
Okay.
You've been continuously filming me.
Yeah, this is a 43 minute video.
Are we done with the...
I think we're done with the video.
All right, cool.
Cool.
Nice talking to you all.
Yeah.
Thank you for joining me too, by the way, for when some bozo finds us on gallery in 50 years.